# Ben A. Gertz

me@bgertz.com

#### **EDUCATION**

Tulane University, New Orleans, Louisiana

B.S., Cell and Molecular Biology and Computer Science Coordinate Major

Anticipated Graduation May 2020

GPA: 3.32 CS Major GPA: 3.72

#### SUMMARY

A highly reliable, detail-oriented software development student with experience in the agile development of cloud-hosted systems using both Node.js and Ruby on Rails. Possesses local experience in using object-oriented programming in Java and Python as well as familiarity with a Neo4j relational database. Utilizes strong interpersonal skills to effectively communicate with managers and collaborate with coworkers. Employed the Microsoft Bot Framework in Node.js to build and manage an Azure-hosted natural language processing chat bot for the Microsoft Teams application. A fast learner and team player ready to contribute to the overall success of a company.

# **EXPERIENCE**

Capstone Collaboration, rMark Bio, Chicago, Illinois Software Development Intern, rMark Bio, Chicago, Illinois

August 2019 - Present May 2019 - August 2019

- In the process of building a recommendation engine for speaker programs using social media analytics algorithms to analyze a Neo4j graph
- Developed a chat bot using the MS Bot Framework and the LUIS natural language understanding engine for a new way to interact with rMark APIs
- Built a RESTful API test harness using the Jest JavaScript testing framework

Genetics Research Intern, Sackler School of Medicine, Tel- Aviv University, Tel- Aviv, Israel

June - August 2018

- Raised and performed experiments on USPC-1 and 2 human ovarian cancer cells
- Results showed a correlation between exposure to IGF-1 and Insulin and expression of a gene responsible for the over production of estrogen, a cause of ovarian cancer

# Camp Counselor, Olin Sang Ruby Union Institute, Oconomowoc, Wisconsin

June - August 2017

- Leveraged organizational and conflict mitigation skills to provide an engaging and safe summer camp experience
- Contacted and arranged enriching camper-led programs with local charities
- Worked cooperatively with camp management and colleagues to ensure a successful overall program

#### CAMPUS INVOLVEMENT

Lab Intern, Tulane Department of Computer Science, New Orleans, Louisiana

August 2018 - March 2019

- Contributed to a web-based tool for the implementation of a researcher's algorithm to determine the likelihood of whether a sequence of amino acids within a protein would be useful in vaccine development
- Employed the Python language using the Dash framework for graphical analysis and presentation
- Tool will allow any lab worldwide interested in using the algorithm to conduct their own research

Campus Legislative Coordinator, Tulane Israel Political Action Committee, New Orleans

May 2018 - May 2019

Secretary, Tulane Israel Political Action Committee, New Orleans, Louisiana

April 2017 - April 2018

- Maintained relationships with local congressmen and senators to inform them on key issues regarding the American-Israeli relationship
- Created and published calendars of events and general meetings

Brother, Alpha Epsilon Pi Fraternity, Tau Upsilon Chapter

# **SKILLS & INTERESTS**

- Computer: Agile, Git, Java, Python, C, Node.js, Ruby on Rails, Windows, Mac and Linux terminal
- Language: Spanish (intermediate verbal, reading and writing)

### RELEVANT COURSEWORK

• Intro to Computer Science I (Python and fundamental concepts), Intro to Computer Science II (Java and OOP, C, Haskell), Systems and Networking (OS fundamentals and IP), Discrete Math, Algorithms, Software Studios (Agile webhosted development)